He was a fashion photographer.
He was long and beautiful and a lot of experience and very cheerful.
He wanted to take a picture of me because he thought I was beautiful.
I think he was maybe the first time ...
I was so new, the body of the 16-year-old he met,
That body was so new.
I was very small and lean for a very long time.
I had a dental position all over my face.
Then at the age of 15, the dental position was taken off and the breasts came,
And something in the body changed.
In the elevator where the girl meets the photographer,
she gets a look she has not really received before.
In the book
The scene is described where A and the girl meet the first time in the elevator.
It is as if she has always known how to do it.
He looks at her, she looks at him.
She makes a small movement with her shoulder.
She wears her pink, white dress and a large leather jacket over.
It is a very small dance.
Choreography is very important to me as I write.
How do the bodies move in the room?
- You see it in front of you?
I always think choreography before I think anything else.
And I did not speak the language, ie French.
I thought when I was going to write this story almost 40 years later,
How do I write a story about a girl in Paris?
I don't take anything from Paris.
I just got lost.
I do not understand.
It was just dark streets.
I just got lost.
I can not write.
I was on that street and walked there.
And then I had forgotten a lot.
Forget is also a way to get lost.
You look in the brain for what happened, what happened, how was it and what ...
Both this and to get lost and to have forgotten very much
I saw a very long time as a problem with writing.
I didn't get it to write!
So it is very often with writing.
I don't know if you have the same experience?
That which is the very problem, what says you can't write this thing
Or that you can't do this thing because you have this problem.
So it is the problem that is the writing itself, the thing itself.
Yes, go into something.
You think, especially with writing and all kinds of art, even life stuff that you are doing.
You can't do this, because this thing is here.
But it is this thing that is the thing.
That's what you should do.
Back to the circular.
What is it getting lost?
Well, it is very often to go in a circle.
This only understands people with bad local minds.
I have a very bad local mind.
It is in the family, I think.
Terribly bad local mind, but what you know when you go very lost
is that you go in a circle.
What if I could write a book that also goes in a circle?
The book takes place on two schedules.
So the adult woman is ... she is like me in quite a few ways.
- What way, then?
She lives where I live,
At a large park in Oslo called Torsjö Park, where she counts the trees.
She suffers from severe depression, or anxiety.
It's pretty much like me.
She also gets lost.
Wil in the memories and lost in the brain.
But then she also tries to find a form of the book.
The book is also about trying to write the book and finding a form.
She quotes, among other things, or I quote, she quotes Virginia Woolf,
As in a fantastic BBC number found on Youtube,
About writing.
She sounds so very nice and noble when she says:
"All the writ is to find the right words and put them in the right sequence."
And it's so wonderful!
- It sounds so easy.
So I have that quote over my desk, but it is also in the book.
Now I haven't really answered your question.
The book's project is in a way,
Can this girl and woman meet in this circle?
And so maybe they can in tiny moment.
But it was worth trying anyway.
- I have a little trouble letting go of this with looks for
Something that becomes so clear in the book is the abyss, which I would at least experience it,
between one then and one now, between a time ...
There are other books that have taken it up, Vanessa Springoras "Consent" for example.
There is a documentary series about Brooke Shields
Which also debuted very young as an actor in these nymphic roles.
It is how striking the pedophile look for young women is at this time.
I'm not so busy with the man's desire in this book.
He is portrayed mostly as either a little crazy and a little crazy,
Or that he sleeps.
- He's closest to a shadow figure?
Yes, he is most clear when he sleeps.
It is the woman in art and novels and in songs.
How many pictures have we not seen from sleeping young girls and a viewing man?
But her desire is extremely important.
She requests him, and the desire is so great and new in this new body
That she needs several bodies to keep all the desire.
Then it happens, when she is with him, that the desire suddenly leaves her.
Then it is just nasty, and she wants to vomit.
So all of these overwhelming, you can say it in Swedish, overwhelming feelings
Available in the body and comes very quickly after each other.
There is a desire, it is not a desire.
It is very much for a 16-year-old girl body to escape.
It does ...
When you take in the girl's desire into such a story, it becomes shortly,
It becomes more dredged.
I do not know if you can say dumb in Swedish, but it will be it anyway.
- It can be said now if not otherwise.
Yes, it is also a great way to say it.
- The science, all that.
- I guess you have received this question a thousand times, or this claim.
The shine and power relations in this book and in this scene,
Especially in this key scene that recurs,
It is impossible, would I say, not to associate with Metoo?
Would it have been possible to write this novel before Metoo?
I tried to write it long before metoo and then I wrote it.
After all, I wrote the story in "the worried" even before metoo, when I wrote.
I would like to say it's not a metoo novel
But that's because I don't like categorization of novels.
I don't like the word autofiction.
I don't like to say that something is a metoo novel.
But then you have to say that there is a lot of autofiction and metoo novel.
One of the books that have been inspired mostly with, both for the worried and this book
Is Margaret Dura's "Lover".
In any case, it was written long before Metoo.
Duras switches between me and she.
I do too.
It is the girl's look that is important in that book.
Not so much the lover.
Yes, I think women have written about these things
And certainly some men too, at all times.
After all, Virginia Woolf writes in "Moments of Being", in her autobiographical depictions,
So she writes about something similar, or about an older relative as ...
It's just that now we say that this is a metoo novel.
This is a metoo novel.
But you say it pretty much about books written by women
Because I think we still have more a tendency to want to categorize,
And she was absolutely right.
So I don't know if it was an answer to your question either.
But it is clear that it
The Medial Metoo debate is mostly on good
but have also had pages that are highly problematic
that has to do with legal security.
that have with the fact that there is actually a big difference between abuse
And stupidity.
And the medial image of the victim role is very often,
It is starting to become a little Victorian for my taste.
We should be sure that the victim is clean.
That there was no Grums there.
And so little that is clean.
I'm the mother of a 19-year-old.
She was 15-16 when I wrote this book.
I am extremely happy that she has a completely different view of what is good.
If a man looked at her when she was 16, a 44-year-old old man
And open the stage room completely.
Was that an answer to the question about why?
-Yes.
Before we round off and fill in with some audience questions here,
Now we have talked a lot about the girl.
You mentioned this look at the parents.
It is also a very nice portrayal of a mother and a daughter
and how the daughter during the pandemic almost takes over this motherly role over her own mother
- Why was it interesting to portray?
It's like the Mor-Dotter books.
It is the adult woman who was the girl and who cannot ...
Who has never been able to talk to his mother about this that happened in Paris.
So in this that was about food and nutrition -
so you could very slowly start a small, little gently call
About things that had happened.
Not only with me but also with her in her youth.
As a writer, I thought was so exciting, as a writer, was exciting,
To portray how conversations come from very small silences and small food lists.
- There is such a stillness over those scenes as well.
- I think it's a great way to round off this call.
Big thanks for that.
Big thanks, Linn Ullman, author of "Girl 1983".
Thanks to you.